Kristijan **Perusko**

software engineer

Contact

347 972 6973 kristijan.perusko@yahoo.com

Links

Github://kperusko Bitbucket://kperusko Linkedin://kperusko

Languages

English, Croatian

Programming

Experience using: PHP, JavaScript HTML & CSS

Familiar with: Java, Python C# (Silverlight), VB.Net Scala, Racket, Octave

Db

MongoDB, MySQL

Os

Ubuntu, Debian Fedora, CentOS Windows

Other

Git, Mercurial, SVN Apache2, RabbitMQ AWS, S3, Heroku

Summary

I've worked as a full stack and back-end software engineer. I prefer working with algorithms, databases, implementing APIs and doing system-wide optimizations, because I find them more challenging and therefore more interesting. This said, I would love to work more with functional programming.

Experience

2008-2014 **Novatec "New Technologies"** Team leader | Software engineer

In-house software engineer for my first two years. Became team leader building client's booking system and multiple customer-facing sites. Also served as project leader where I gathered requirements from clients, mentored junior engineers, planned and implemented critical features. My responsibilities included administration and optimization of MongoDB and MySQL DBs and Ubuntu/Debian servers.

2007-2008

Responsible for Windows administration and user support, configuration and management of infrastructure and equipment in 8 remote offices. Managed system upgrade for compliance with EU customs legislation.

2005-2007 Vlado elektronika

Sofware and electrical QA engineer

Veleuciliste u Rijeci (Rijeka College)

Created hardware testbed and software for computer aided testing of intrusion alarm system. This system automated 90% of the tests and lowered the testing time by 60%.

Education

2013 BS of information tehnology

Silverlight 5 and MS Sync Framework

2002 **Electrical engineering**

DC servo driver controlled by IR remote

Online courses

M202: MongoDB Advanced Deployment and Operations

MongoDB

MongoDB

Principles of Reactive Programming

École Polytechnique Fédérale de Lausanne

Machine Learning

Coursera Stanford University

Interactive Programming in Python

Rice University

M101JS MongoDB for Node.js Developers MongoDB

MongoDB

Functional Programming Principles in Scala

École Polytechnique Fédérale de Lausanne

Startup Engineering

Stanford University